## **Josh Timmons**

#### **FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPER**

406-425-3820 timmons.joshua@icloud.com joshtimmons.dev

in <u>LinkedIn</u>



### **Profile**

Extremely motivated Full Stack Software Developer seeking a career in the software field. Completed Lambda School's 9 month Full Stack Web Development course, during which time I spent 8 hours a day learning React, Node.js, Python, and much more. 2 years of experience in real estate, 3+ years in customer service and 1 year in marketing.

#### Skills

JavaScript

React.js w/ Hooks

Redux

• Node.js

• Express.js

Postgres

• CSS & Preprocessors

• SQLite

• Git

# **Projects**

ROAMLY - GITHUB - LIVE - 2019 | Tech Used: React w/Hooks, Node.js, Express.js, GraphQL

This is an app that allows you to build a complex itinerary for traveling!

• Built on a team of 5 developers over 5 weeks.

 Individually completed Popular Destinations component.

HOW TO - GITHUB - LIVE - 2019 | Tech Used: React, Axios

A web app where you can browse how-to videos or upload your own!

• Individually completed front-end of project in 4 days.

• Worked with another developer to connect backend.

REPLATE - GITHUB - 2019 | Tech Used: Node.js, Express.js, Postgres

A web app that allows restaurants to post food for donation and allows a volunteer to claim food.

• Individually completed back-end of project in 4 day.

• Worked with 2 frontend developers to connect the frontend.

# Experience

TEAM LEAD, LAMBDA SCHOOL, SAN FRANCISCO, CA - 2019 - PRESENT

• Review my 8-9 students code daily, help debug students code, lead daily standup meetings and meet with students 1:1 to ensure their understanding of programming concepts.

REAL ESTATE AGENT, CROWN REALTY, BILLINGS, MT - 2017 - 2019

Helped answer questions and troubleshoot problems for an average of 10 clients each day.

INTERNET MARKETING ASSISTANT, ARCHIE COCHRANE FORD, BILLINGS, MT – 2012, 2016

- Planned out and created an average of 5 videos from start to finish each month.
- Planned with my team of 4 people creative content to post to various social media outlets.

DETAIL TECH, ARCHIE COCHRANE FORD, BILLINGS, MT - 2010-2014

• Worked with 150 clients a week to ensure their vehicle was satisfactorily delivered.

#### Education

Lambda School, Online - Full Stack Web Development - Certificate - 2019

Dark Horse Institute, Franklin, TN - Audio Engineering – Certificate - 2015